gpsworld.com 2018-10-09

# North Coast Media Privacy Policy

### North Coast Media, LLC Privacy Policy

Last revised: May 25th, 2018

#### Table of Contents

  * Collection of Personal Information
  * Personal and Financial Information Sharing
  * Aggregated Information
  * Information on Children
  * Updating Personal Information
  * Third Party and Affiliated Links
  * Cookies
  * Opt-Out Option
  * Security and Encryption
  * Privacy Statement Coordinator

The following Privacy Statement summarizes the various ways that North Coast Media LLC (“NCM”) treats the information you provide while using [www.northcoastmedia.net](http://www.northcoastmedia.net/) or any other NCM site. It is our goal to bring you information that is tailored to your individual needs and, at the same time, protect your privacy. This Privacy Statement does not cover information collected elsewhere, including offline and on sites linked to or from any of our sites.

Please read this Privacy Statement carefully. Your use of, accessing, and/or registration on any aspect of our sites will constitute your agreement to this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not use our sites. If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us by e-mail at [privacy@northcoastmedia.net](mailto:privacy@northcoastmedia.net)

In addition to reviewing this Privacy Policy, please read our [Terms of Use.](http://northcoastmedia.net/ncmtos.html) Your use of our sites constitutes agreement to its terms and conditions as well.

This Privacy Statement may be modified from time to time; the date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page, so check back often. Any change, update or modification we make will be effective immediately upon posting on our site(s). If we are going to be using the information collected from users in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will send affected users written notice of the change by e-mail. Continued access of our sites by you will constitute your acceptance of any changes or revisions to the Privacy Statement.

**Collection of Personal Information**  

In general, you may visit our sites without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information.

As you browse our sites, we collect log file, IP address of your computer, and other standard tracking data we use to evaluate site traffic and usage patterns.

Such information is aggregated with tracking data from all site visitors. We may use the information to personalize our sites according to your preferences based on the aggregated information. We also use the aggregated information to evaluate products and services we may offer to you. These products and services may be targeted to users who fit a certain general profile category, which may be inferred from information provided to us by a user, may be based on usage patterns of particular users, or may be based on your activity. We do not provide Personal Information to any ad networks for use other than in connection with the Services.

Portions of our sites may require you to give us personally identifiable information, such as your name, job title, company, physical mailing address, e-mail address, telephone and fax numbers and, if applicable, financial information such as your credit card information, for, among other purposes:

(i) registration for attendance at certain NCM trade shows, conferences, webinars and events;  
(ii) subscriptions to our publications, including e-newsletters;  
(iii) promotions from NCM for webinars, books, editorial content, advertiser opportunities, etc.; and from third-party marketing partners; and  
(iv) use of our websites, including quizzes, surveys, contest entries and feedback submission.

If you communicate with us by e-mail, post messages to any of our websites or forums, or otherwise complete online forms, surveys or contest entries, any information provided in such communications may be collected as personal information. You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit most of our sites, but you may be unable to access certain options and services.

If you elect to provide us personal information, we use it to deliver the services you’ve requested and carefully selected related materials. If you submit financial information, we use that information to verify your credit and collect payments for your purchases, orders, registrations, etc.

**Personal and Financial Information Sharing**  
We may share your personal information with our affiliates and with our partners, including our exhibitors, sponsors and advertisers, for marketing, advertising, and/or product/service offering purposes, and with others who are licensed to access your personal information by any of the foregoing. Also, we rent e-mail lists compiled from e-mail addresses gathered from our sites. While we will seek to require all such third parties to follow appropriate privacy policies and will not authorize them to use this information except for the express purpose for which it is provided, NCM does not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of third parties.

If you do not wish to have your personally identifying information shared, or if you do not wish to receive future commercial communications from us by e-mail, you may unsubscribe or opt-out, as described below – see “Opt-Out Option.”

We also allow access to our database by third parties that provide us with services, such as development services, but only for the purpose of and to the extent necessary to provide those services.

In addition, we reserve the right to use the information we collect about your computer, which may at times be able to identify you, for any lawful business purpose, including to help diagnose problems with our servers, to gather broad demographic information, and to otherwise administer our sites, or if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on NCM or to protect and defend the rights or property of NCM, or to enforce our terms of service.

In addition, as our business changes, we may buy or sell various assets. In the event all or a portion of the assets owned or controlled by NCM, or any subsidiary or affiliated entity, are sold, assigned, transferred or acquired by another company, the information from and about our sites’ users may be among the transferred assets.

**Aggregated Information**  
While your personally identifying information is protected as outlined above, we reserve the right to use, transfer, sell, and share aggregated, anonymous data about our users as a group for any business purpose, such as analyzing usage trends and seeking compatible advertisers and partners.

**Information on Children**  
As a business-to-business company, we have created and maintain sites that are not intended for use by children, particularly those under age 13, and we do not knowingly collect information from children. On-line registration and website usage is restricted to adults who are professionally engaged in the businesses we serve. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information or use any public discussion areas, forums and chats comprising part of our sites. Minors between the ages of 13 and 17 must get the permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before making purchases, including subscriptions, on our sites. In the event that we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible.

**Updating Personal Information**  
Many of our Site functions (but not all) provide you with the option of correcting, updating and modifying your personal and/or financial information, or visitor profile, at any time and as often as desired. The only item of information you cannot change is your username ID selected at registration.

__Right to Access Your Data:__ You can ask us for a copy of your personal data and we will comply with your request on an individual basis in a format suitable for the type of data requested. If you would like to submit a request, please contact us by e-mail at [privacy@northcoastmedia.net](mailto:privacy@northcoastmedia.net).

**Third Party and Affiliated Links**  
Our sites may from time to time contain external links to other websites, including suppliers, advertisers and affiliates. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the content of, or information gathered by, these other websites. We do not endorse any of these websites or the products or services associated with such websites merely because they are linked to any of our sites. In addition, users of our sites should also be aware that, when you voluntarily disclose personal information in chat areas or bulletin boards, that information may be collected by others and may result in unsolicited messages from others.

**Cookies**  
A “cookie” is a bit of data sent by a website through the browser to the computer of the user visiting the site, and enables our sites to return the results the browser expects. We may use temporary, session-specific cookies to ensure visits to our sites is smooth and customized for the visitor – for example, to control the display of ads, to track usage patterns on our sites, to deliver editorial content, and to record registration and personalization information. Such cookies allow us to provide a visitor’s browser with information tailored to the visitor’s preferences and needs. We also may use permanent or persistent cookies that remain on a visitor’s computer after the visitor leaves our sites. We use this data on an anonymous basis and we do not correlate this information with personal data of any user.

We may, from time to time, work with advertising companies who are developing banner ads for our sites. These ads may contain cookies that may be sent to your browser through the banner ads. We do not have control over cookies placed by our advertisers, nor do we have access to any information their cookies may collect.

Most website browsers automatically accept cookies, but you may be able to turn off the cookie acceptance option in your browser’s settings. If you wish to disable cookies, refer to your browser help menu to learn how. However, disabling the cookie support function of the browser may prevent some portions of our sites from functioning properly, and you may not be able to utilize fully all of our sites’ features and information.

**Opt-Out Option**  
Visitors to our sites can decide if they want to receive targeted promotional information from NCM or targeted promotional information sponsored by our marketing partners. Should visitors receive promotional e-mail from NCM, any e-mail that is sent will include instructions on how to be removed from our promotional email list.

If you do not wish to have your personally identifying information shared, or if you do not wish to receive future commercial communications from us by e-mail, you may change your preferences at any time simply by: (i) writing to us (and please include your e-mail address), or (ii) by following the unsubscribe instructions contained within the e-mail you receive from us. We will update your preferences as soon as is reasonably practicable. If you have registered on any part of our sites, please use the mechanism on our sites that allows you to change or update your profile, preferences or information, if available, to keep all such data accurate and up-to-date. The only item of information you cannot change is your username ID selected at registration.

Please note that if you opt-out as described above, we will not be able to remove your personal information from the databases of third parties with which we have already shared your personal information (i.e., to which we have provided your personal information prior to our receipt of your opt-out request).

If you choose to remove yourself from our lists by opting-out as described above, we will make every reasonable effort to forward your opt-out request (including your e-mail address) to the specific third-party marketer whose offer you received from us prompting your opt-out or unsubscribe request, so that it can include your e-mail address on its own do-not-email list; however, NCM does not bear any responsibility for ensuring that any third party complies with your opt-out or unsubscribe request vis-à-vis its own lists.

**Security and Encryption**  
We use procedural and technical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss, theft or unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy, including encryption, “firewalls” and Secure Socket Layers. We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. However, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet.

**Privacy Statement Coordinator**  
If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us by letter at the address below, or by e-mail at [privacy@northcoastmedia.net](mailto:privacy@northcoastmedia.net).

__California Privacy Rights:__ Under California’s “Shine the Light law” (California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84), California residents are entitled to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, information explaining the categories of personal visitor information that we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, as well as provide contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: 1360 E. 9th Street, Suite 1070, Cleveland, OH, 44114.

We read every message submitted and try to reply promptly.

**North Coast Media, LLC**  
1360 E. 9th St. 10th Floor  
Cleveland, OH 44114  
© 2012 North Coast Media, LLC Privacy Statement

Revised and Posted As Of: May 25th, 2018
